おやっさん
了解
人命救助　急げ
ゆっくり　ゆっくりだ
現れた軍隊に勝利した日本は
第三偵察隊の隊長となった伊丹は
人ではなく　エルフだが…
門の向こうに自衛隊を派遣することを決定
日本に突然開いた　異なる世界からの門
調査をしている最中　集落を襲う炎龍を発見
襲われた村にはたった一人　生存者らしき女性が
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流，禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕，尽在 www.kamigami.org 和微博 @诸神字幕组
特に何も望む事なんてない
日听 阿布 小伍  翻译 Akashi はばやし 校对 はばやし  时间轴 神埼魯蒙  压制 咸鱼
身の程は知っているさ
A gate to another world opened in Japan without warning.
Japan, having defeated the invading army from the other side,
そんな僕でさえも　奥の方に
decided to send the Self-Defense Force through the gate.
Itami, having found himself the commander of Recon Team Three,
譲りたくない
discovers a dragon attacking a settlement.
行こう　ゲートはあるらしい
守るって案外と難しいね
There at the settlement, he finds a lone, female survivor.
諦めるわけじゃないけど
青い空の果て繋がった道の行方
一時と分かり合えない
Pops!
だけどいいんじゃない
Slowly! Slowly!
開いた扉は全てを変えてゆく
それは暁のように
We need a rescue! Hurry!
Roger.
Not for a human, though. She's an elf.
Thus, the JSDF Fought There!
バイタルは何とか持ちそうです
とにかく　濡れた服を脱がせて
Thus, the JSDF Fought There!
ごめん　切るよ
to
Thus, the JSDF Fought There!
kk
u
Thus, the JSDF Fought There!
ni
na
Thus, the JSDF Fought There!
to
ni
I don't really have anything I'm wishing for
Thus, the JSDF Fought There!
mo
no
kk
zo
to
u
mu
kk
ko
ni
to
u
na
n
te
na
i
ni
na
mo
ni
no
mo
zo
no
mu
zo
ko
mu
to
ko
na
to
n
na
te
n
na
te
i
na
mi
no
ho
do
wa
mi
i
sh
I pretty much know my place.
i
t
te
i
no
ru
mi
sa
ho
no
do
ho
wa
do
sh
wa
i
sh
t
i
te
t
i
te
ru
i
sa
ru
so
n
na
bo
ku
so
sa
de
Even so, I think deep down that I don't wanna let anything go
sa
e
om
n
ou
so
o
ku
no
na
ho
n
u
ni
bo
na
ku
bo
de
ku
sa
de
e
sa
om
e
ou
om
o
ou
ku
o
no
ku
ho
no
u
ho
ni
u
yu
zu
ri
ta
ni
It seems I'm only playing "the good girl".
ku
yu
na
i
ii
ko
tte
zu
i
yu
to
ha
a
ru
ra
sh
i
ri
zu
ta
ri
ku
ta
na
ku
i
na
ii
i
ko
ii
tte
ko
i
tte
to
i
ha
to
a
ha
ru
a
ra
ru
sh
ra
i
sh
ma
mo
ru
t
i
Protecting something is harder than I thought,
te
ma
an
ga
i
to
mu
mo
zu
ma
ka
sh
i
ru
ne
mo
t
ru
te
t
an
te
ga
an
i
ga
to
i
mu
to
zu
mu
ka
zu
sh
ka
i
sh
ne
i
a
ki
ra
ne
But it's not like that means I'm gonna give up!
me
ru
a
wa
ke
ja
na
i
ke
ki
do
a
ra
ki
me
ra
ru
me
wa
ru
ke
wa
ja
ke
na
ja
i
na
ke
i
do
ke
ao
i
so
ra
no
ao
ha
At the far reaches of the blue sky - the end of these connected roads,
te
t
su
na
ga
t
i
ta
ao
mi
chi
no
yu
ku
e
so
i
ra
so
no
ra
ha
no
te
ha
t
te
su
t
na
su
ga
na
t
ga
ta
t
mi
ta
chi
mi
no
chi
yu
no
ku
yu
e
ku
hi
to
wa
e
People still won't come to understand one another... but I'm fine with that
wa
ka
ri
a
to
e
hi
na
i
da
ke
do
ii
n
to
ja
na
i
hi
to
wa
ka
ri
a
e
na
i
da
ke
do
ii
n
ja
na
The door I'll open will have everything changing,
i
na
hi
ra
i
ta
to
hi
bi
i
ra
hi
wa
su
be
te
i
o
ra
ka
e
ta
te
i
yu
ku
to
ta
bi
to
ra
bi
wa
ra
su
wa
be
su
te
be
o
te
ka
o
e
ka
te
e
yu
te
ku
yu
so
re
wa
a
ka
so
ku
t
Just like the break of dawn!
su
re
ki
so
no
yo
u
ni
wa
re
a
wa
ka
a
t
ka
su
t
ki
su
no
ki
yo
no
u
yo
ni
u
Episode 3  Fire Dragon
Her vitals are steady.
Take her wet clothes off.
Sorry. I'll have to cut this off.
It's an elf, Commander! And a blonde, no less!
エルフっすよ隊長　しかも金髪の
This is awesome! Hooray for the Special Region!
すごいですね　さすが特地ですね
気分は出てきたな
I sense good things coming our way.
Dude, you're into elves?
お前　エルフ萌えか？
Excuse me.
失礼します
How's she doing?
どう？あの子
Her body temperature is returning to normal.
体温が回復してきてます　命の危険は脱しました
She's out of mortal danger.
それはよかった
That's good.
それで　これからどうしましょう
So, what should we do now?
Let's see...
そうね…
First, find me a pair of dry boots!
とりあえず僕に濡れてない半長靴をちょうだい
集落は全滅しちゃってるし
The settlement's been wiped out.
ほっとく訳にはいかないでしょ
We can't just leave her.
Let's take her back as a refugee.
保護ということにして連れ帰りましょう
I knew I could count on you to say that.
隊長ならば　そうおしゃってくださると思っていましたわ
I'm humane, aren't I?
僕人道的でしょ
Gee, I don't know.
さぁ　どうでしょうか
I thought it might be rude of me to bring up
二尉が特殊な趣味をお持ちだからとか
the fact that you have some odd
あの子がエルフだからとか
interests, or that she's an elf.
いろいろと理由を申し上げては　失礼になるかと
We're now returning to
以上　これよりコダ村経由で　アルヌス駐屯地へ帰還します
Alnus Station via Coda Village.
ね　隊長
Hey, Commander.
We won't run into a dragon or something
猫耳娘より前に　ドラゴンが来たりしませんよね
before we get to meet a cat girl, right?
Don't jinx it.
言うなって…
What if that actually happens?
本当になったらどうする
Coda Village
何と…
What?!
集落が全滅した
The settlement's been wiped out?
大きな鳥　いた
We saw large bird.
森　村　焼けた
Forest and village burned.
炎龍…
A Fire Dragon.
No.
そんな…
It can't be.
まさか…
炎龍　火　出す
Fire Dragon breathed flame.
人　沢山　焼けた
Burned up many people.
そして　女の子を一人　助けた
We saved one girl.
この娘一人か　痛ましいことだ
Just this one girl?
What a tragedy.
Can she stay in village?
この子　村で保護…
We can't take in an elf.
エルフを保護はできん
Besides, we must flee this village while we can.
それに　我らもこの村から逃げ出さねばならん
村　捨てる？
You abandon village?
We must.
そうだ
Once a Fire Dragon tastes the flesh of humans or elves,
エルフや人の味を覚えた炎龍は
また村や町を襲って来るのだ
it will keep attacking villages and towns.
Run for it, everyone!
みんな　逃げるよ
Aye, sir!
よっしゃ
はいさ
All right!
よーし
Hey! Dammit!
おのれ　もう
Dammit all!
おのれ　これ…
Ow!
It hurts!
痛ーい　痛いの
Master, we can't carry any more.
お師匠　これ以上積み込むのは無理
No! I need my books!
嫌じゃ　本は必要なんじゃ
Lelei, isn't there anything we can do?
レレイ　どうにもならんか
Certainly,
確かに　この場合貴重な書物を優先すべきと考える
I believe we should prioritize the most valuable books.
そうじゃ
That's right.
You sure are smart, Lelei.
頭が良いな　レレイ
But why now?
しかし何で今頃…
Damn that Fire Dragon!
炎龍め
Showing up fifty years early...
五十年も早く出てきおって
お陰でいい迷惑じゃ　まったく
Look at all the trouble it's causing us.
お師匠も早く乗ってほしい
I wish you would sleep already, too.
Huh? What do you mean by that?
何を言うっておる？
I'm not interested in mounting little girls like you!
わしはお前に乗っかる様な少女趣味はないわい
I'd rather mount a curvy woman like your sister.
どうせ乗るなら　お前の姉の様な
ボン　キュ　ボーン
止めんかっ！
Stop! Magic is sacred!
魔法とは神聖なものじゃ　濫用するものではないのじゃぞ
Do not abuse it!
やれやれ　冗談の通じない娘じゃのう
You sure can't take a joke.
I blame you as my educator, Master.
お師匠から受けた教育の成果
He won't move.
動かんねぇ…
We must be carrying too much.
荷物が多すぎた様じゃのう
You were the one who said to pack all this.
詰めっと言ったのはお師匠　この事態は予想されていた
This was to be expected.
Not to worry. I am a sorcerer, after all.
心配するではない　わしらは魔導師
Isn't magic sacred?
「魔法とは神聖なものじゃ　濫用するものではないのじゃぞ」
Something not to be abused?
Those were your words, Master.
お師匠が言った言葉
じゃが…
But...
But in this case, we have no choice.
でもこの際仕方がない
すまんかったね
Sorry.
It's fine. I've always known that this is simply how you are.
いい　お師匠がそういう人だと知っている
What's going on up ahead?
この先はどうなっているんじゃ？
Cato-sensei! Lelei!
カトー先生　レレイ
One of the carts was carrying too much.
実は荷物の積みすぎて
車軸の折れた馬車が道を塞いでいるんです
Its axle broke, and it's blocking the way.
Helping with evacuations is part of your job!
避難の支援も仕事のうちだろう
Commander Itami, please ask the village chief to move out.
伊丹隊長は村長から出動の要請を引き出してください
Got it.
わかった
聴いたことのない言葉じゃのう
I've never heard such a language.
I've never seen such clothes.
見たこともない服
黒川は怪我人がいないかを確認
Kurokawa, make sure no one's injured.
Roger.
了解
Soldiers? Women, too?
兵士？女もあるのか？
Master, I'm going to go take a look.
お師匠　様子を見てくる
Wait, Lelei!
いやちょ　ちょ　レレイ
危険な状態
She's in danger.
This girl has a concussion.
この子は脳震盪起こしています
It's possible she has a fractured skull as well.
頭骨にひびがはいてる可能性も
You, stand back. It's dangerous.
君　危ないから下がって
Doctors?
医術者？
あなた　大丈夫？
Are you all right?
Those people...
あの人たち
They saved me.
私を助けた
隊長　あの人たち　まさかずっと俺たちが面倒を見るんですか？
Commander,
don't tell me we're going to be taking care of all these people forever.
Aren't there any lords or royalty around here?
この辺には領主とか貴族とかいないんですか？
About that...
それね
さっき村長に話し聞いた
I talked to the chief about it.
None of the lords in this region ever came back
この地方の領主一統は
この前アルヌスの丘に出陣して以来　誰一人帰ってこないだとさ
after they were sent to fight at Alnus Hill.
It seems the whole of Coda Village is on the run.
コダ村が村中で逃げ出しているらしい
This is a good opportunity.
これはいい獲物だ
Do we have enough men?
こっちの頭数足りねぇんじゃ
集めりゃいい
Just find more.
There are plenty of stragglers left
この前の戦の敗戦兵が  この辺りにはごろごろいる
from the recent battle.
Round them up, and we could take on
そいつらを束ねりゃ
村どころか町ごとを襲う大仕事も
not just a village, but an entire town.
We could overthrow the local lord!
領主を追い出すのも夢じゃねぇぜ
From a bandit leader to a lord...
盗賊の頭から領主さまか…
I like it.
悪くない
おじさま方
Gentlemen,
thank you for tonight.
今宵はどうもありがとう
命をもってのご喜捨を賜り　本当にありがとう
Thank you very much for
giving your lives so selflessly.
The All-Father is
主神はあなた方の振る舞いがたいそう気に入られてぇ
very pleased with your actions.
He now requests
おじさま方をお召しになるっておしゃられてるのぅ
your presence.
I am Rory Mercury,
私はロゥリィ・マーキュリー
Apostle to the Dark God, Emloy.
暗黒の神　エムロイの使徒
She's one of the Twelve Apostles! Rory the Reaper!
十二使徒の一人　死神ロゥリィ
She's...
ありゃ…
She's wearing the Emloy shrine oracle uniform!
エムロイ神殿の神官服だ
Run!
逃げろ
I don't think so.
駄目よぉ
Thus, the JSDF Fought There!
Her vitals are steady.
バイタルは安定　意識もまもなく回復すると思います
She should regain consciousness soon.
Yeah?
そうか
But man, this sucks.
しかし　参ったなぁ…
Do they have a destination?
これ　どっか目的地あるんっすか？
Apparently not.
ないらしいよ
え　ないっすか？
They don't?
Being on the run is exhausting.
逃避行ってのは　なかなか消耗するものだね
I'm thirsty.
のどが渇いたわい
It seems we won't rest for a while yet.
しばらく休めそうもない
Push with all your might!
力の限り押せ
Show us what you're made of!
根性を見せてみろっ
あえていうなら
You could say they're going to keep running
炎龍が襲ってこないとわかるまで逃げるってことらしい
until they know the Fire Dragon isn't coming, it seems.
I guess refugees are the same anywhere you go.
難民っていうのは　どこの世界でも似たようなもんなんだなぁ
No good, Commander. The axle is broken.
だめです　隊長　車軸が折れています
We would only be waiting to die if we stayed.
ここにとどまっても死を待つだけだ
背負える分だけでも持って逃げるんだ
Shoulder what you can and keep going.
わかりました
All right.
Why did you make them burn it?
どうして火をかけさせたのですか？
They refused to keep moving.
荷物を前に全然動こうとしないんだもの　それしかないでしょう
It was my only choice.
Can't we ask for backup vehicles?
車両の増援を頼めないのですか？
We're technically past the front line.
一応　ここ　フロントライン越えてるんだよ
俺たち程度なら見逃しても
They might let us off the hook,
but the enemy might move if we brought a huge unit here.
大規模な部隊が侵入したら　敵さんも動くかもしれない
Then it'll be spontaneous battles,
その後は偶発的な衝突
無計画な戦線の拡大　戦力の逐次投入
more unplanned combat, and runaway military costs.
Before you know it,
瞬く間に拡大する戦禍　巻き込まれる村人たち
there'll be destruction,
and the villagers will get caught in the middle.
Just thinking about it is terrifying, apparently.
考えただけでぞっとするってさ
So you were told, huh?
そう言われたんですね
だから　俺たちが手を貸す　それぐらいしかできないんだよ
That's why the most we can do
is give them a hand.
Huh?
あれ？
Someone's coming from up ahead.
前方に何やら
Crows?
カラス？
Let's see...
えーと…
A Gothic lolita girl!
ゴスロリ少女
あなたたち　どこからいらしてぇ　どちらへ行かれるのかしらぁ？
Where do you come from?
Where are you going?
What'd she say?
なんて言った？
I don't know.
さあ
She appears to be a child.
見た目は子供のようですね
It's the oracle!
神官様だ
Oracle! Oracle!
神官様
神官殿
神官？
Oracle?
Where did you come from?
どこから来たのぉ？
From Coda Village.
コダ村からです
We fled from the village.
村を逃げ出しておりまして
There was a Fire Dragon. We had to run.
炎龍が出てきて　みんなでここまで
They appear to be praying to her.
祈りをささげてるように見えますね
So there's some religious reason for that weird outfit?
あの変な格好は宗教的な意味があるってことか？
この変な人たちはぁ？
Who are these strange people?
They saved us. They're good people.
助けてくれたんだ　いい人たちだよ
嫌々連れて行かれるわけじゃないのねぇ
So you aren't being forced out of your village.
Nope.
How does this move?
これ　どうやって動いてるのかしらぁ？
I don't know.
わかんない
But it's a way comfier ride than our carts.
でも　乗り心地は荷車よりずっといいよ
Oh?
へー
乗り心地がいいのぉ？
A comfy ride, huh?
I'd like to see
私も感じてみたいわ　これの乗り心地
how it feels to ride it, too.
Hello. How are you?
ちょ　ちょっと待って
Wait a second.
This is a really tight fit.
窮屈なんだよ
Move, please.
退いてくれ
羨まし過ぎます　隊長
That's no fair, Commander!
Just get off!
いいから　降りろ
Oh?
あら？
Hey, don't touch the pistol!
こら小銃に触るな
I said don't touch that!
触んなって
No fair!
羨ましいっす
I'm not enjoying this.
嬉しくねぇし
I told you not to touch it!
触んなって
羨ましいっす
No fair!
もういいから　降りろぉ
Just get off already!
It's Roche Hill.
ロチェの丘だ
We've walked that far?
ここまで歩いたのか
ちょっと雰囲気変りましたね
The scenery's starting to change, huh?
Yeah.
We're pretty far from the village now.
村からもかなり離れたからねぇ
I wish this evacuation was over already.
このまま逃避行も終わりにしたいよ
No kidding.
全くです
こっちの太陽って　日本より熱くないか
Isn't the sun hotter here than in Japan?
なっ
Battle stations!
戦闘用意
本物の炎龍じゃ
It's a real Fire Dragon!
I've never seen one before!
わしも見るのは初めてじゃよ
Fighting giant monsters is a Defense Force tradition!
怪獣と戦うのは自衛隊の伝統だけどよ
Go, go!
走れ走れ
LAV, create a diversion!
ＬＡＶ　牽制しろ
キャリバー
Caliber!
Pay it no mind! Keep firing!
かまうな　当て続けろ
Fire, fire, fire!
撃て撃て撃ちまくれ
Breath incoming!
ブレス来るぞ
We don't stand a chance against that flame.
あの炎食らったら終わりっすよ
でも　キャリバーも効かねぇ
But the .50 calibers aren't cutting it, either.
Shit! What do I do?
くそ　どうすりゃいい
ono
Since when are you...
いつの間に…
ono
Eye?
目？
All units, aim for the eyes!
全員　目を狙え
It stopped! Katsumoto!
動きが止まった
勝本
Oh, wait. Shoulder check.
おっと
後方の完全確認
Do that first!
遅いよ
You snatched the trigger!
ガク引き系
外れるぞ
It's a miss!
I-Is it over?
お…終わったんすかね
I think so.
たぶんな
生存者の大半は近隣の身内のもとに身を寄せるか
Most of the survivors are going to relatives nearby,
or take refuge at a village or town somewhere.
どこかの町や村に避難するそうです
I doubt they'd know anyone there, though.
町だって　知り合いいないだろう　大丈夫なのか？
Are they gonna be all right?
They have bigger problems.
それより　それ以外がもっと問題です
Kids and old folks with no families.
身内が亡くなった子供とお年寄り　ケガ人か
And casualties.
I'm sorry to be so cold,
薄情ですまんが
こちらも自分のことで精一杯でな
but we have to take care of our own, too.
We can't afford to take care of them, as well.
その者らまで心配してやれる余裕はないのだ
置いていくの？
Will you leave them?
あんたらには心から感謝しているよ
We sincerely thank you.
さようなら
Bye!
元気でな
ありがとう
Thank you!
助かったよ
You saved us!
それで　どうなさいますか　伊丹二尉
So what do we do, Lieutenant Itami?
ま　いっか
Oh, well.
Don't worry. Leave it to us.
大丈夫　任せて
あれ　何　この空気
Huh? Why are you all acting like that?
いいえ
Nothing,
I just knew you'd say that.
二尉ならそうおっしゃると思ってました
I'm humane, aren't I?
僕　人道的でしょう
All aboard!
全員乗車
We're headed back to Alnus!
これより　アルヌスに帰還する
unmei niwa sakaraenai ne deatteshimatta
I guess I just can't fight my fate - we've already met!
運命には逆らえないね
出会ってしまった
何があるかわからないけれど
nani ga aru ka wakaranai keredo
I don't know what might happen,
君と出かけよう
kimi to dekakeyou
but I'm heading out with you!
心踊る遠い景色は
kokoro odoru tooi keshiki wa
There's something a bit different
なんだか違って
nandaka chigatte
about the far off scenery,
doa o akete itsumo no choushi sa
But once we open the door, we're back to
ドアを開けていつもの調子さ
どうぞよろしく
douzo yoroshiku
our usual pace, so let's keep on together!
mada kimerarenai sanpo koosu
We still can't decide which course to walk
まだ決められない散歩コース
いろんなものが多すぎて
iron na mono ga oosugite
There are just too many things to consider.
光りの渦に吸い込まれて
hikari no uzu ni suikomarete
Pulled into a whirlpool of light,
また迷ってるの
mada mayotteru no
We're still undecided!
走り抜けたあの瞬間は
hashirinuketa ano shunkan wa
Amidst a sweet, sweet scent,
甘い甘い香りの中で
amai amai kaori no naka de
We can feel a new future within this place.
新たな未来　ここに感じてる
arata na mirai koko ni kanjiteru
Upon a song, disappearing high into the sky,
tondekieru uta ni noseta
But the moment we manage to run on through
飛んで消える二人の星座
空へ空へきれいな星に
sora e sora e kirei na hoshi ni
I'll cast a spell that sparkle brightly,
キラキラ光るように
kirakira hikaru you ni mahou kakeru kara
I'll cast magic which shines bright
魔法をかけるから
Episode 4  To Unknown Lands
次回　「門」
Next time on GATE:
"To Unknown Lands."
見知らぬ地へ